Did you know that the sea air
is a natural antihistamine?
The salt clears the passages.
- Hey, Cho.
- What do we got?
Alton Creek. He's a big-time
divorce attorney.
It's hard to say which one
of his many enemies
would want him dead.
His speedboat's down there.
Cause of death?
Well, he's not
dead yet.
Somebody just threatened
to make him that way.
Threatened? Since when do
we roll for death threats?
When the threatened man
is a rich establishment lawyer
with juice.
This one's on you, Cho.
Apparently one of your
confidential informants
knows reek.
She told him we could help.
- Summer.
- Uh-huh.
Summer?
That's a nice name.
She's a working girl.
Been a C.I. for a few weeks.
Surprised she knows
a high-end guy like Creek.
She's moving up.
[Creek]
'Where are you?'
Hi. Yeah. Uh, Mr. Creek,
w-we're walking to you now.
[Creek]
'You're late.'
It's a long drive
from Sacramento.
We got here as soon
as we could.
That's it? Moron, someone's
trying to kill me.
And the CBI needs to do
something about these threats
or I will call my good friend,
the attorney general..
[explosion]
[theme music]
[crackling and whooshing]
- Uh..
- His leg?
Was that a shark?
So much for
professional courtesy.
[Rigsby]
So forensics finished
their search of the water
near the explosion
and confirmed
that the body parts belonged
to Alton Creek.
Did they... find them all?
Most. And the arson squad found
traces of c-4 in the debris.
Guy never knew
what hit him.
At least he was dead
when, you know..
...the shark ate him.
Okay, um, anything else?
Uh, time frame.
Security cameras covering
the yacht's berth
were down for repairs between 11
last night and 7 this morning.
Killer had to have planted
the explosive then.
- Is that luck or planning?
- Don't know yet.
So who wanted this guy dead?
He's a divorce attorney.
Who didn't?
Does he have any family?
Nope. We're trying to find his
law partner, Lawrence Dersh.
He's not at any
of his three houses.
[woman speaks indistinctly]
Ah.
Maybe Summer'll know.
I asked her to come in.
Kimball Cho.
It's been a while.
You're late.
You know sharks can have up
to 3000 teeth?
Five rows of 'em.
Are you gonna actually
help on the case?
'I could actually use
your help, too.'
Special agent Darcy.
How's the federal authorities?
I haven't seen you for, uh..
Since, what..
The Panzer business, right.
Actually, that's why I'm here.
We just took over the case.
SFPD wasn't getting
anywhere.
Can I ask you
a couple of questions?
- Um, we're kind of--
- 'Oh, of course.'
Uh, whatever you need.
Take a seat.
I'll, I'll make tea.
Is this an official inquiry?
Cop to confidential informant?
You'll get paid.
Now did Creek tell you
who wanted to kill him?
Wasn't that kind
of relationship.
How's your back?
It's fine.
Whatwas your relationship?
He used to be a client.
We weren't close,
but I liked him.
Well, you seem to be
one of the few.
Yeah, well,
Alton was...abrasive.
He was a real lawyer,
you know?
Wasn't really happy unless
he was arguing about something.
- Girlfriend?
- New one every month.
You know his law partner,
Lawrence Dersh?
No, not really.
But you know what?
Al was bitching
about Dersh last week
said they got in a fight
over money or something.
Could Dersh be the one
who threatened Creek?
Maybe. I mean,
it was pretty hard-core.
- You heard the threat?
- No. I saw it.
We were coming back
from this party
and it was sitting
on his front doorstep.
A pig with a big old knife
in his head.
I told him to go to the cops,
but he said no.
Couple days later, he asked if
I knew any cops who were cool.
I couldn't think of any
so I told him
to talk to you guys.
Look, Red John was
an accomplished killer
no doubt, and I applaud you
for ridding us of him.
But he is not
in the same league
as the San Joaquin killer.
'Red John was
a common sociopath..'
...lazy, sloppy, delusional.
'You really have no idea
what you're saying.'
And only
a little while later..
[tea pouring]
Hmm.
The man who killed Panzer wanted
it to look like Red John
'whom you shot and killed
last spring.'
Lapsang souchong.
I think you're gonna like it.
Here we go.
Your point?
Well, it's an odd chain
of events, isn't it?
Mm.
[slurps]
Yeah, I guess. Odd happens.
What does it matter
who killed Panzer?
He was the San Joaquin killer.
So you said, but I studied
Panzer very carefully.
There's not a lot of evidence
to support that.
Not your kind of evidence.
He was the San Joaquin killer.
I agree.
It is possible, but his murderer
still has to be apprehended.
Why?
Because killing someone
without government
permission is wrong?
Was there something that
you wanted to ask, agent?
Are you sure the man
you killed was Red John?
[swallows]
Yes. I'm sure.
[clears throat]
Then we have a copycat.
can you think of anyone
who would wanna do this?
Someone that wanted to avenge
Panzer's crimes, I'd imagine.
Well, who else thought that
he was the San Joaquin killer
aside from you?
Good question.
You figure out
the answer to that
I think you'll probably
have your killer.
But surely the motive
is to avenge the insult
to Red John, right?
I mean, look at the...
the cutting patterns.
Clearly, our suspect
is someone who studied
Red John obsessively.
Well, R-Red John..
...he was the type to attract
followers, um, a-admirers.
He had a particular style..
...a style that people wanted
to, to copy, you know?
'Not unlike Elvis.'
Alright.
Well, thank you
for your time.
I'm staying
at the Oakview Inn.
If you can think
of anything else
please give me a call.
Agent Lisbon.
Nice lady.
Nice?
That's all you're gonna say?
She's nice?
Great legs.
[indistinct chatter]
Don't you think it's time to
tell the truth about Red John?
[door closes]
Well, the truth is
I killed Red John.
I mean, you can ask anyone.
It was on the news, Lisbon.
But you think he's alive.
I toldyou that.
You, Lisbon. Nobody else.
And it's better that way.
Then why make him
re-emerge?
You manipulated Panzer
into insulting Red John
so Red John would kill him.
I didn't know how else
to stop Panzer.
He would have just
kept on killing.
And now you've got the FBI
asking awkward questions.
You've kept this from the team.
It's not good.
It's lucky they don't know,
'cause if they knew
they'd have to lie,
wouldn't they?
And this way, they can tell
what they think is the truth.
Do you know how messed up
that sounds?
Yeah.
What is wrong
with the simple truth?
Telling people he's alive?
I told a jury
that I shot him dead.
Where does that leave me?
It's not good.
No, no, not great.
Their partner dies,
and they throw a party.
Nice.
Hey, so you're stranded
on a desert island
with Attila the Hun,
Joseph Stalin, and a lawyer
and you got a gun, with only
two bullets. What do you do?
- You're telling a lawyer joke?
- Yeah.
No.
Lawrence Dersh.
You're a tough man to find.
You're here about Alton.
Awful thing. Just awful.
But business
is business, right?
This is our
yearly retreat, officers.
It's been scheduled for months.
The employees are scared.
I have to show them that
business is still strong
even with Alton gone.
He'd want that, I promise you.
Sir, where were you between
11 P.M. and 7 A.M.?
Um, whoa. Sorry.
Flag on the play.
My client won't be answering
any questions right now.
Your client?
Colette Santori. I work
with Larry at the firm.
White-collar crime.
Fast track to partnership,
right, Colette?
Yeah, if you play
your cards right.
No, uh, in-house dating,
Larry. Rules.
Well, as you can see,
Larry's had a few
and is saying
some inappropriate things.
Not a good time to talk
to the police.
Hey, now.
But I would be happy to set up
an interview for tomorrow.
Sure. No problem.
Just one thing.
Who had reason
to want your partner dead?
I have no idea.
Like I said..
'...tomorrow.'
Thanks for your time.
[computer chimes]
What the hell?
That's weird.
'It's late, Grace.
What are you still doing here?'
Just...had stuff to do.
[mouse clicks]
[chimes]
Hey, take a look at this,
would you?
[groans]
Somebody uploaded a file
onto the major crime server.
The file was transferred
from outside CBI
and that's not possible.
At least it shouldn't be.
That's that "I dare you" thing?
Well, let's take the dare.
[mouse clicks]
[horn honks]
- Isn't that the FBI agent?
- Darcy, yes.
What is going on?
[car door closes]
[alarm chirps]
[lock turns]
[door squeaks]
[door closes]
[chimes]
Somebody just uploaded
a text file
to the same folder
as the video.
Open it.
Uh..
Oakview Inn. Oakview Inn.
Quick, let's go.
Let's get outta here. Come on.
[engine shuts off]
[[car door closes]
[rattling]
- Grace, Grace, Grace.
- Alright, hold on.
Don't move. Federal agent.
CBI. We're friendly.
Don't shoot.
Patrick?
Susan.
Sorry about your door.
[door closes]
Creepy.
Looks like you're my knight in
shining armor, Patrick.
Hmm.
So, I go to CBI
asking about a copycat
and CBI is sent this
weird stalking video of me.
Panzer's killer's taken
an interest in you.
It's dangerous.
I-I think you should
get off the case.
You should give it
to someone else.
Come on.
This weird video
makes me wanna
go after after that creep
even harder.
I, uh...this is
a dangerous situation.
We're not talking about
just some peeping tom.
This is a stalker. It's
a totally different pathology.
Goodnight.
I can take care of myself.
I appreciate
your help tonight. Thanks.
That video..
It was Red John.
Yes.
Red John
is stalking Darcy.
[sighs]
Yeah.
And you didn't tell her.
Are you crazy?
If I told her, she, she would've
just gone harder at the case.
She's not really
the type to stop.
Mm. Is this
about helping Darcy
or keeping Red John
for yourself?
What? This is not about me.
Of course I'm worried about her.
"She's cute.
This is gonna be fun."
That message,
that was meant for you.
Yes, that was
a message for me.
Red John is trying to form
a closer relationship with you.
Yeah, well,
there's no relationship.
What if Red John took
murdering Panzer
as some kind of invitation?
You manipulated
a serial killer.
There's gonna
be consequences.
I didn't have a choice.
I had to stop Panzer.
I will try and get Darcy
off the Panzer case..
...before Red John hurts her.
I hope you can.
You had a fight
with your partner, Alton Creek?
A disagreement, agent.
Not--
I'd like to hear it
from him, Ms. Santori.
It was a disagreement.
Not a fight.
About money?
Go ahead.
You can answer.
Yes, we argued over money.
Some of his clients were
behind on their bills
and I told Al
to get on them about it.
Look, he was my partner
for 15 years.
I had nothing but love
for the guy.
'This is from the security
camera outside your building'
'the day before Creek died.'
Doesn't look much like love.
What were you really
arguing about?
I told you.
Money.
You know who
you should look at
is that hooker
he hung out with.
Summer Edgecombe?
Summer... Autumn,
something like that.
She's got
a terrible temper.
If there's nothing else,
we'll get going--
Just one more thing.
You lied to us yesterday.
We asked if anyone
wanted Alton dead
and you said no,
but wasn't that a lie.
Do you know who sent this
to your partner?
Did you do it?
That is disgusting.
And I certainly
didn't do it.
Are we done here?
- So?
- So I asked around.
"did Dersh happen to mention
Al's little secret?"
and by little, I mean big,
'cause he had to know.
What secret?
Cost you $1,000 to find out.
Thousand dollars?
And dinner
at a nice restaurant.
Five hundred and a pizza.
Six hundred, no mushrooms.
Deal.
I hate mushrooms.
What can you get
for $127.68?
You can go crazy
at olive garden.
Not me. Creek.
Van Pelt looked
into his business records
and there's something weird.
Up until six months ago
every week, he put in
for reimbursement by his firm
for $127.68 for expenses.
So he was hiding whatever it is
from his partner.
Yeah, but what can you
buy for $127.68?
I don't know. Creek was
hiding something else.
Our C.I. Found out he had a big
gambling habit. Poker, mostly.
- Illegal?
- Very.
San Francisco has an underground
club in the tenderloin.
Creek had lost plenty lately.
That could have been why
he and Dersh fought.
Yeah, but a few days later,
Creek won 50 grand
at Texas hold'em, which turned
out to be a bigger problem.
- Why?
- He won it from Brock Marx.
Bay area crime lord.
Marx accused Creek of cheating,
threatened to kill him.
Felony narcotics, assault
assault with a deadly,
and attempted murder.
A mobbed-up guy like this
could leave a pig's head
outside somebody's door.
Go pick him up.
He's in the wind. Parole officer
hasn't heard from him in weeks.
Crap.
We think we can find him
at this gambling club
but SFPD Is busting
the place next week.
- Asked us to go in quiet.
- How quiet?
[techno music]
Hey.
There's Marx.
You okay.
You no.
I wanna play craps.
This is the only table.
Too bad.
It's okay, baby.
I'll play for the both of us.
I bet I do better than you would
have done anyways.
Go get a drink.
This won't take long.
[man] $63.
Hi.
[indistinct conversations]
What is it?
What happened?
Darcy's okay.
It's not her.
Not directly anyway.
Panzer..
The gift that keeps on giving.
Do you remember Tom Maier?
He was the father
of Panzer's first victim?
Sure. Nice man.
He killed himself today.
Oh.
[speaks indistinctly]
[sighs]
Oh, well.
[chips rattling]
Try again.
Thanks.
Side bet?
Like?
[whispering indistinctly]
You have a bet.
[chuckles]
'Eight the hard way.
Winner, Eight.'
Ohh.
[exhales deeply]
'And the shooter passes. We got
a new shooter coming out?'
Pay up.
Right now?
Why not?
Here?
So you're pretty much
tall, dark, and handsome.
- Yeah.
- I like that.
Police. Brock Marx.
You're under arrest.
[handcuffs clicking]
For what?
Parole violation.
We need to ask you a few
questions about a murder.
[exhales deeply]
Nice work.
Thank you.
What'd you whisper
to him?
Wouldn't you like to know?
[dramatic music]
'Morning, Lisbon.'
Uh, I need to borrow
your office.
Too bad. I'm busy.
What costs $127.68?
Creek spent that much every week
for months and was hiding it.
Until three months ago. Hmm.
Anyway, your office?
Are you gonna actually
help with this case?
Well, as soon as I can get
Darcy off Panzer's case.
Mr. Jane.
Mrs. Maier, please,
thanks for coming to our office.
Have a seat. Lisbon, this is
Teri Maier, Tom Maier's wife.
Mrs. Maier, we are
so sorry for your loss.
The gardener found him
in the backyard.
Tom made sure it wasn't me
who found him.
'Yeah.'
The coroner's office
hasn't released the body yet.
I need to bury him.
Of course.
I'll check it out immediately.
Thank you.
Okay. I'm so sorry
for what happened.
It was the guilt.
It ate him up like a cancer.
Every day Tom got smaller
and smaller
until finally he left.
Did he happen to
leave a note?
No.
But honestly, I haven't checked.
He felt bad.
So the only thing he could do
was hang himself.
He was in so much pain,
and all I feel is angry.
We will do everything
we can
to get the coroner to release
the body as soon as possible.
Okay. Thank you.
Uh, I got a lot to do,
so have a nice day.
- Jane?
- Yes.
Is there something
you wanna tell me?
Deniability, Lisbon.
Deniability. Your best friend.
'Sent to Creek
before he was killed.'
A warning of what's
to come, huh?
Make him afraid, paranoid?
This is just your style..
...cheap, gruesome, sadistic.
You got a question for me?
Or you just wanna chat?
You can keep that.
Lisbon, it's Jane. Let's have
lunch in San Francisco.
What do you say? Call me.
Teresa, aw, can't tell you
how great it is to see you.
Partnered with this one
for three years.
Oh, I know. Patrick Jane.
Bobby Wilson.
So how's it goin'?
How's the big old CBI?
Oh, you know, it goes.
FBI's all over us
about this, uh, Panzer case.
Oh, feebs. They were jackbooting
about it over here, too.
Anyway, what
do you say, Bobby?
Could you show us your, uh,
file on the Panzer case?
Uh, yeah, sure.
Just have CBI file a request.
It's form 29.
Oh, of course.
Yeah. Yeah.
We were hoping that
maybe we could, uh..
...expedite the process,
you know, talk to you.
We're under the gun
with time.
He's okay, Bobby.
Did you find any..
You know, never mind.
Deniability.
Guess what we found out?
California bar was investigating
your law partner
over his gambling.
That's what your fight was
about last week, wasn't it?
Yes. Alton was
out of control.
- So you lied to us.
- Don't answer that.
If al got disbarred,
that was the end of your firm.
He'd become a liability.
And how do lawyers
deal with liability?
Oh, don't worry.
It's not a lawyer joke.
[Van Pelt]
'They get insurance.'
You insured Alton Creek's life
for $10 million.
'Four weeks ago.'
Larry?
I didn't have time
to mention it.
It's common for businesses
to have a "key man" policy.
Al was "key."
Uh, you know what?
We're done here.
Admit it. Alton was worth more
to you dead so you killed him.
- I said we're done.
- Fine.
Let's go, Mr. Dersh.
Agent, seriously, I don't think
Larry is capable of this.
Don't be naive.
Men lie...and kill.
Maier?
Yes. Thomas.
Right in here.
Five minutes.
Thank you.
Hey, we've had Brock Marx
in the box for hours.
The guy won't talk.
Ah. Theory number one..
Crime lord. Pig's head. Yes.
We've got his law partner
as well.
Insurance motive.
You want to question him?
Kind of busy right now.
Why don't you guys
get your suspects together?
I'll meet you back here
in some time. I promise.
- Where are you going?
- Got a find a hobo.
Do some errands. Then I gotta
run by this flower shop, too.
What? Find a hobo?
Flower shop.
[knock on door]
[clacking]
[cell phone rings]
[ring]
Patrick, it's Susan.
Ah, Susan.
What do I owe the pleasure?
'Well, I'm callingyouback.'
Oh, that's right. Yeah.
'I wanted to let you know
I went down to the SFPD.'
'I didn't find anything.'
'I know.
So, why'd you go?'
Well, this Panzer-Red John
copycat thing
has me very intrigued.
'I wanna help out as much
as I possibly can.'
So, uh..
Susan, you still there?
Listen, I need to talk to you
about a couple things.
- I've gotta go.
- Wait. Patrick?
[door squeaks]
[door closes]
'Patrick, are you there?'
[whispers]
'Bye.'
[keys clatter]
'Hello?'
[door closes]
[elevator bell dings]
- Patrick.
- Susan.
I was hoping we could
talk some--
Jane, they're waiting
for you.
Hang on one second.
I have a few questions--
You're more than welcome to wait
in the interview room
but this one hasn't done squat
on our murder investigation
and he's damn well
gonna help.
Yes, I damn well am gonna help.
I'm sorry.
I won't be long.
Thanks for rescuing me.
Shh!
- Hey.
I didn't call you in.
Oh. Mr. Jane asked me
to come in.
Hi. Okay, folks.
Let's get straight to it.
Patrick Jane.
Nice to meet you.
Do you prefer eggs
for breakfast over cereal?
Cereal.
Hardened criminal like yourself.
That's very interesting.
What's your favorite
legal objection?
Better to be feared or loved?
You don't have to answer that.
'Summer.'
Patrick Jane.
Pleasure to finally meet you.
Hi.
You..
'You are
a borderline sociopath.'
Extremely violent.
But not our killer.
You were jealous
of the victim's talent
his skills
in the courtroom
but he never, uh,
bought you flowers.
Flowers? No.
Yeah. The flower shop
nearest your office
uh, sells a dozen red roses
for a very reasonable price
of $127.68.
It was flowers?
Seriously?
Yes. Our romantic victim
bought them once a week.
A secret relationship
he couldn't disclose..
An illicit one.
Maybe not that illicit.
No offense. But how many men
do buy roses for hookers?
Oh. I don't hook anymore.
But they do buy them
for girlfriends.
Girlfriends they can't have
under certain rules.
You killed Alton Creek.
[scoffs]
Uh, that's ridiculous.
I'm an officer of the court.
I see homicidal rage,
betrayal.
You were lovers.
Yes, that's right.
And he dumped you.
Hence, the pig's head.
Pig for a pig.
Ms. Santori, we'll have
to ask you a few questions--
You killed Al?
You bitch!
[Patrick]
Oh. Hello.
[grunting]
Have a nice day.
Ugh!
Al was an okay guy.
Why the hell did you kill him?
- I got this, Summer.
- "An okay guy"?
He said he'd marry me,
the bastard!
And then he changed his mind.
He just wasn't ready,
wasn't sure of his feelings.
Oh, a divorce attorney who was
holding out for true love..
The affair ended months ago,
long time to hold a grudge.
Can you take her
to holding, please?
Hey, I waited for him
foryears.
I put my career on hold
to be with him.
I wanted a family,
and now it is too late.
He took away my life!
And turns out,
all he wanted was a hooker.
I'm not a hooker, bitch.
Susan, did you wanna
talk now?
I don't have any time.
Field office just got a tip
on the Panzer murder.
Homeless guy found a bag
of stuff in an alley in Fresno.
Tip from a hobo?
My people are on it.
A bag of clothes with blood
spatter on it and a knife.
Looks like it could be
the knife that killed Panzer.
Mm. Copycat's sloppy
if it's his knife.
Red John would never
have been that careless.
Forensics is running
the blood now.
Oh, get this.
The alley is in the neighborhood
near the Maier home.
Thomas Maier? No.
- Yeah. The San Joaquin killer.
- I know who he is.
He's the father
of the first victim.
I-I-I don't buy that.
Maier killed himself
yesterday.
We're going to the house now
to search it.
Okay. Good luck.
I have a confession to make.
When Tom killed himself
'part of me was angry at him
for being weak.'
But now I know how strong
he was.
Now I know.
The FBI found this letter
in molly's room.
It's from Tom.
It's important that you all
hear this
so you can understand.
"my dearest Teri..
"if you are reading this
"you know what I have done.
"I have avenged myself
against Jim Panzer.
"Jim was the man who killed
our molly.
"When I saw him on TV
that night, I knew.
"I knew he'd killed her.
"I can't explain how..
except to say
that molly's heart cried out
to me, and I knew."
[sobbing]
Please.
"Killing the man who murdered
our daughter
"is the best thing
I will ever do.
"I'm at peace.
"I'm just sorry
that I'm leaving you alone
"and I hope you forgive me
"and that in some way,
this letter brings you..
...some kind of comfort."
[paper rustles]
"Love, Tom."
[man]
"Lord, make me
an instrument of your peace.
"where there is hatred,
let me so love.
And where there is darkness,
light. Amen."
That's very nice of you
to give her that letter.
Oh, well, it's the least
I could do.
My god, poor woman.
Yeah.
So...the case is closed.
Once we got the labs back,
it was a slam dunk.
'The prints
on the knife, Maier's.'
'The blood was Panzer's.
It was denatured'
'but it was definitely his.'
But why Red John? Why..
Why would he copycat
a dead man?
I don't know.
Maybe he felt like he had to
emulate a monster to hunt one.
So he picked the biggest one
he could find.
One thing I can't
figure out, though
is why he was stalking me,
and why the video?
Hunting monsters
changes you.
Went and killed himself
the very next day.
I hope he found peace
in the end.
Goodbye, agent Darcy.
Did it change you, Patrick?
Hunting a monster?
Of course.
Be well, Susan.
Ithaschanged you,
you know.
Darcy's off the case, Lisbon.
She's safe.
And what about you?
How is Red John gonna feel
when he finds out you spoiled
his fun with agent Darcy?